<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Chapter>
    <Heading>Introduction</Heading>

    <Section>
        <Heading>Francy</Heading>

        &Francy; emerged from the need for a lightweight framework to construct interactive graphics in GAP, 
        primarily for the web, particularly within &Jupyter; environments.
        Although there was an initial attempt to repurpose the XGAP package, the absence of a standardized 
        data exchange format between GAP and the graphics renderer, coupled with the project's straightforward 
        requirements, led to the development of a new GAP package. Explore &Francy;'s functionality on these
        <URL Text="Jupyter Notebooks">https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/gap-packages/francy/master</URL>.
    </Section>

    <Section>
        <Heading>Applications</Heading>

        &Francy; has numerous applications and can be used to create graphical representations of data structures. 
        It facilitates navigation and exploration of properties or relationships within these structures.
        Consequently, &Francy; enriches learning environments where GAP offers a vast library of functions 
        implementing algebraic algorithms alongside extensive data libraries of algebraic objects.
        &FrancyMonoids; and &SubgroupLattice; are some example packages using &Francy;.
    </Section>

    <Section>
        <Heading>Functionality</Heading>

        &Francy; offers an interface for drawing graphics using objects. This interface relies on basic principles of
        drawing and graph theory, enabling the creation of directed and undirected graphs, trees, line charts, 
        bar charts and scatter charts.
        These graphical objects are depicted within a canvas, which includes a space for menus and to display informative
        messages.
        Users can interact with the graphical objects within the canvas by clicking, selecting, dragging, and zooming.
    </Section>

    <Section>
        <Heading>Installation</Heading>

        This package requires the &GAP; packages &JupyterKernel;, &json; and &uuid;, all of which are distributed
        with &GAP; by default.
        &Francy; requires &Jupyter; to be installed on your system. Please note that you need to run the installation
        commands from the same python version &Jupyter; is installed on.
        Currently, &Francy; is supported on &Jupyter; Lab and the new Notebooks (&gt;=7.0.0).
        In order to install or update &Francy;, please run the following command to download the latest version
        available from <URL>https://pypi.org/</URL>:
        <Log>
            mcmartins@local:~$ pip install -U jupyterlab-francy
        </Log>
        If you want to use it on the old &Jupyter; Notebooks (&lt;7.0.0), please install the latest supported version 
        available from <URL>https://pypi.org/</URL>:
        <Log>
            mcmartins@local:~$ pip install -U jupyter-francy
        </Log>
    </Section>

    <Section>
        <Heading>How it works</Heading>

        &Francy; requires a rendering package to display graphics. &Francy; provides by default 3 renderers based on
        D3.js, Vis.js and Graphviz, for rendering the semantic model representations, identified by the MIME type 
        'application/vnd.francy+json', produced by the GAP package. 
        Renderers can be switched at any time using the user interface, by selecting 'Settings' and then 'Renderers' 
        in the main menu.
        This library is distributed both as a browser module and as a &Jupyter; extension. It can be used in the browser 
        in non interactive mode (meaning no communication with GAP, the semantic model is loaded, e.g., as a json file),
        or within &Jupyter; environments, in interactive mode, using the &JupyterKernel;.
        For more information, please check the 
        <URL Text="JavaScript Documentation">https://gap-packages.github.io/francy/doc/js/doc/index.html</URL>.
    </Section>

    <Section>
        <Heading>Publications</Heading>

        <URL Text="ICMS 2018">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-96418-8_42</URL>
    </Section>

</Chapter>
